[Music]
Hi gas, you all must have seen this news by now
that after the announcement related to the insurance sector in the Union Budget 2023, the
stocks of the insurance sector will be
Bajaj Finserv HDFC. The
third segment will understand whether it is going to have an
impact only on the insurance sector.
In the fourth segment, we will
make our strategies and in the fifth segment,
which is a very important segment,
we will see majorly all the stocks which will be
related to this,
along with the name of each stock,
what strategies we have to do in it, whether to buy, hold, or
sell. So this entire video is going to be
very interesting, but
you will be able to benefit from it only if you
watch the video completely from start to end. Along with this, there is
a very big Major
Launcher, our end is Major Amrit Card
Discount. So what is this Major Bananas
Launcher, what is the Major Amrit Card
Discount? Know this also by watching this video completely
or by contacting us
on 9821611667. Let's start, but before we start,
please if you have  If you have
not subscribed to the channel then
press the subscribe and bell button below and
subscribe and if you like the video then
like and share it.
Now we understand the first segment, what was the
major announcement related to the insurance sector
in this budget, so if I
say insurance and ask you to pause the video and comment below, then
what will click in your mind first, please
pause and comment, so if I say
insurance, then what will come to the mind of most of the Indians will be
10-20 ATC ATD and
after this protection life insurance health
insurance will come now, then 10-10 B ATC
ATD, these are the sections which are
insurance related and which till now
help us in tax saving, so an
announcement related to this section has been made
in this union budget due to which the entire
insurance industry has been shaken, these
stocks have seen a huge fall,
so the first announcement of thesis Nirmala
Sitharaman, in that she said that
starting from 1st April 2023,
if any individual takes a traditional insurance
plan and the entire  If the premium that he is paying in a year for a
single policy
or the total premium that he is paying for all the traditional policies that he has taken
from 1st April 2023 goes
above ₹5 lakh, then
what was the case till now at the time of maturity of these insurance policies was that
when these insurance plans (traditional
insurance) matured, then it used to be paid
10-10d, that is, it used to be clocked in for 10 years,
so there was a 10+10d section under which the
maturity processing was 100% tax
free, but in this budget, as
I told Mrs. Nimila, the premium that you are paying above ₹5 lakh, starting from
1st April 2023, the
new policy that you are taking, then the
processing of that premium will not be tax free,
so majorly, those who are not taking the
benefit of this section for taxation, they will
not be able to take the benefit of the section, it
was not of the sector but it directly
impacted the insurance sector, in that
he said that  In the new tax regime, the tax free limit would be up to ₹7 lakh. Right, in the new tax regime, there is no benefit of ATC or all these sections. In the old tax regime, if you are investing up to ₹1.5 lakh in ATC, then it is deducted from your income and you are able to save tax on it. What comes under this ATC is investment in insurance and there are many other ETC instruments too, but under 80d, if you are taking medical insurance, then up to ₹25,000 is deducted and then after that your tax is implemented. Now, since the new tax regime will seem more attractive to people, they will go for it and there is no investment under 8080 in it. So again, insurance would be impacted. This project is being done, which is the third major one. There is no announcement, but the announcement has not been made. This is the problem of the people that any health insurance related to ATC insurance is not available.  The
announcement was made, which actually
after some timepass, it was expected that the
amount of 25000 for health insurance would be increased
or the GST levied
on health insurance would be removed because
due to that many people do not take it or
because in the new tax regime the tax
bracket has been increased to 7 lakhs, so
in ATC, the amount of those who are opting in the old tax region,
their ATC will be increased from 1.5 lakhs to 10
lakhs or 2.5 lakhs, in this way nothing
happened,
so this is our
part one, it is coming on the D segment, so
what will be the basic impact of this announcement or these three things on the insurance sector, so whenever
we talk about insurance, you too must have been
approached by any bank or any insurance, the major terms which are used for
insurance, the
middle class people of India
generally buy insurance policies to avail the benefit of ATC
or the individuals who are
high-sold
If they are professionals or businessmen, then basically they invest a huge amount in big ticket insurance to get the benefit of 10 lakhs, so they invest in big ticket insurance, which Nirmala Sitharaman has capped, if it goes above five lakhs then that tax benefit will not be available under 10-20 lakhs, so this is the insurance sector would be impacted by these announcements coming on to the segment three, will it be only the insurance act, then it is not at all like that that majorly no one has paid attention to, the banking sector is also going to be impacted very majorly because you must have heard this word a lot, the banks which sell insurance are called bank's power, so it comes from the insurance company and the major revenue of the banks is the power of the bank, it comes by selling insurance, so definitely when the sale of insurance will drip then the banks will also be affected, how bank's power helps the banks in their propotablity, there are two slides on your screen.  Please take a look.
I got this slide of Major Axis Bank and SBI and
I have attached it with you. Rest of the other
banks, you must have experienced it yourself.
All the banks focus mostly
on insurance sales because
their properties increase a lot.
Coming out of the fourth segment,
our streets should be because
this is the most important for us. Right now the
first statement I will tell you is don't
jump on the conclusions very soon
because this is just an announcement. All the
insurance companies
because insurance is very big in India,
so obviously it is said that all the banks of India will be
affected, be it private sector banks, be it
pre-school banks, all NBFCs, this will be a
factor, all the insurance companies will be affected.
So these people have said
including IRDA that they will
take this proposal to Mrs. Nirmala Sithan that for the
first 10 years, they have capped it at ₹5 lakh and
investment in traditional plans should start in one year.
From April 23, the capping of ₹5 lakh should be increased to ₹
10 lakh. Secondly, they will come up with this proposal that just
like they have
increased the limit up to ₹7 in the new tax region, the
ATC limit should be increased in the old tax region which would
again help in the sales of
insurance products. Thirdly, it is also being said that
they will be asked to
increase the capping of health insurance as well.
ATC plus GST should be made free.
And I have said that right now I do
not have any such proposals. If
proposals come to me, I will evaluate them and then
decide. Because as much
research I have done, this ₹10 lakh cap was for Rs.
5 lakh, that is why we brought it by
controlling most of the people to evade tax.
And anyway,
they have declared that
it will have some impact on the death benefit.
You will get the full ₹10 lakh and
benefit of all the things on the death benefit. So basically, the intention is obviously to stop this and that is why
this proposal is being made again.  It may be
revaluated, it may be
withdrawn, the second part is that if
we see that even if it is not withdrawn and it
remains, then how much will it affect the
insurance sector in the long term.
So, if we talk about insurance sales, then first of all
in insurance, life insurance is
just a part of it for insurance, motor
insurance, health insurance and a number
of insurances which contribute to the entire insurance
business, out of which
motor insurance is third party
insurance in India, so definitely
all these sales will keep on happening and will have to increase
and during the period of time, second, if we talk
about these 10-10 day closes, then the
close has come above ₹5 premium, so these are
hardly very small tickets which
contribute hardly 5 to 10%
over and that impact will be there in insurance sales or revenue
because of this, this properly
HDFC Life has
also given a declaration, their CEO has said that this much of our
business will be impacted due to this new reform,
please it is not very much
and new products should be introduced in a new way  Of
products, but they will definitely cover it, they will have
less overhead, apart from that, India
is such a progressive country,
Amrit tomorrow we are starting and
in India there is a lot of other insurance like life
insurance, health insurance, motor
insurance and other kinds of insurance, there is a huge
market in which this is being
tapigrasali and industries have a lot of
customers who will do
their business by contacting them, so the insurance business
in the long run is definitely going to grow in India,
if we talk about health and jobs, then
corporates give insurance to their
employees, so that business has to grow anyway,
but of course we cannot reach conclusions very soon, so
what should be our action in which individual company,
this is our last segment and date, I
think it is most important for you,
but of course I got that done on my analysis, so that is why
I explained the entire background to you,
so you also do you, so before I tell you, the
type of individual stockwise steps should be buy, sell, hold, our
I would like you to tell us what our Major
Amrit Kaul Bonanza announcement
So, there is a lot of request from all of you that I want a module from you in which you teach us how to do multibag picks, so of course it takes a lot of tramandal, a lot of analysis, there are a lot of steps and I am bringing a proper complete module in which I will tell you the whole thing step by step, there will be a lecture on fundamental analysis, you know, there will be a lecture on financial analysis, there will be a lecture on technical analysis and in the overall stock market, first of all I attack the stocks which are analyzed in these three ways, there will be a lecture on that, so all these things would be there, apart from that, question answer is a complete module, you can enroll in this module and get benefited and the sooner you do it, the more benefit you will get because we have kept early bird discount in it, so quickly if you want to take benefit of it, then pick up your phone and contact us on 982161167, but wait, there is one more discount which is there tomorrow, I will tell you that as much as  We also have research plans for
investment, for trade and for all, you
know multibag service and all, so if
you enroll in that now, then we will give you a special
Amrit discount in the language of
RIM Minister Narendra Modi because
he said that starting is the Union Budget, the
first is Amrit Kalka, so we would also
like to give on Amritsar because this is like a very good
type of correction in the market and
our long term role map of Amrit Kalka,
so this is the time when should invest
in Indian Army, so if anything is
holding, you just want to and there is a
discount, so I hope after this you would
definitely start, if you are waiting, then
that opportunity is right now and you will
definitely graph it, so pick up your phone and
contact us by
calling or WhatsApping on 98161167,
coming out of the last man, which are such
stocks which we should buy at this time,
so I strongly hope that Bajaj
Finserv, HDFC,
Axis Bank, ICICI Bank are
giving you a very good opportunity right now  And you should start
accumulating but of course you would use this
rule, you have not forgotten, I have
said it after a long time, by buy average, accumulate
hold, so this rule should be followed by replying, while buying it now, coming
on the second, which
stock you have to watch, that is,
you have to add it to your watchman right now, keep
watching and when you get an opportunity in it,
you have to add it, but
you can get a very good opportunity in it very soon,
so there are HDFC Life and
ICICI Prudential Life
Insurance, which are coming in the third degree, in which they are
strongly full, if you have heavy, then if
you are in profit, then exit right now
and do not make a new entry at all, so there are two
stocks which are strongly
full in this category, the first one is LIC,
apart from the insurance sector, there are many other
sectors also, like I made a stock
in Adani, their investment exposure
etc., so one is LIC and the
second one is Max Life, so apart from this,
if there is any stock on which you  If you want to know
what your action should be then
tell me by commenting below and if you like the video then
please do
tell me by commenting below and if you
want a video on this topic next then please do
tell me that too so I hope you like this video and
you can benefit from it, thank you so much